[♪ mysterious music playing]
[both gasp]
[cape rustling]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[Patchwork Bear 1 growling]
[roaring]
-[Elymas grunting]
-[sword slashing]
[grunts, yells]
-[gasps]
-[monster grunting]
-[monster growls]
-[Elymas grunts]
-[sword slashes]
-[monster groaning]
[Ruche panting]
[RUCHE] Acrobatic Amble!
[panting]
[grunts]
-[Golden Raana croaks]
-[Ruche giggles]
Doppellusion!
[gasps]
[croaking]
[grunts]
[croaks]
[ELYMAS] Shadow Stomp!
[struggling]
[panting]
Dice Thrust!
[grunts]
[yells]
[squeals excitedly]
[grunting]
[AUTOMATED VOICE] Critical.
[Ruche grunts]
[grunts]
[Golden Raana groans, thuds]
[ELYMAS] The only possible way
I'll be able to beat it
is to throw
three more Magic Stones.
But Dreamlords
regenerate very quickly.
If I take too long, I'm screwed.
[gasps]
[Embryo babbles, laughs]
[ELYMAS] No way.
It shouldn't use Sylph Cutter
with us positioned like this!
[Embryo screeches]
[Elymas gasps]
It's no use.
I can't dodge it!
[Elymas yelling]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[screams]
[laughing]
[Elymas groans]
I'm losing consciousness.
- [heart thumping]
- My heart
is pounding out of my chest.
And I can feel my legs
growing weaker.
[heart thumping]
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Status effect, Stunned.
[ELYMAS] I see.
In a situation like this,
a stun is fatal.
[straining weakly]
Who knows?
Maybe my starting Luck value
was set too low.
Well, Ruche,
I should have asked you to stay.
Come on.
Let's defeat it together!
[RUCHE] Did ya call for me?
[straining]
[gasps]
Thanks for asking me
to join your party!
[Embryo babbling]
Doppellusion!
♪
Wait. What are you doing here?
I thought you took those guys
and fled this dungeon! [gasps]
[Ruche sobbing]
[gasps]
[RUCHE] There's just one path
out of here.
And I sensed
you weren't following us.
So I made sure those two
made it somewhere
they'd be safe.
Then I hurried back
to check on you.
[sobs] You said
you'd just buy us time.
So what made you stay back
and keep fighting
instead of running away?
I was...
being stubborn.
You have to turn back,
all right?
[Ruche crying] No way!
I'm staying.
We can be stubborn together!
[gasps]
[whimpering]
[ELYMAS] No. Don't touch those.
I want you to pick up
every single coin
you toss down there.
-[Cline grunts angrily]
-What's the matter with you?
You honestly thought
you could throw them
all over the ground
and say it's some kind of gift?
[RUCHE] You helped me
when no one else would.
♪
You risked your own life
just so I could have a chance
of escaping unharmed.
Now go. Get them outside!
[RUCHE] From the moment
I joined your party,
you said you needed my powers.
So I won't abandon you! [sobs]
[gasps]
If I were the type
to run away...
then I'd have quit adventuring
a long time ago!
[gasps]
[both gasp]
But I only had
one effective attack,
and it isn't going
to work anymore.
For us to reach the Embryo,
we need long-range skills
that we don't have.
After all you've done,
you're just giving up?!
Even when
I called myself useless,
you still relied on me
and saw the potential
that I had inside.
[ELYMAS] It's all right.
[gasps] Ruche, I...
[whimpering]
Truth is, I need you
more than you know.
[sighs] So now, you should
let me help you again.
[Embryo babbling]
Doppellusion.
[ELYMAS] I see.
Ruche is far more
than I imagined.
[♪ rousing music playing]
-Help me, Ruche.
-[gasps]
Because I need your power
more than ever.
[chuckles happily]
♪
We'll beat the Embryo
side by side!
Yeah! Let's do this, Mr. Elymas!
[♪ opening theme song playing]
♪
[grunts]
Hey, they're coming!
[Elymas grunts, pants]
[ELYMAS] Shield Bash!
[grunts]
Now, Ruche!
[panting]
[yells]
I've got this.
I know I can do it.
[Embryo growls]
[both gasp]
[Embryo roars]
[exclaims]
[RUCHE] This feels like
it'll never end.
Yeah. Trying to defeat
the Tin Knights is pointless.
We can't beat them.
Not in a drawn-out fight.
We should focus
on taking down the Embryo.
[Ruche gasps]
Do you have a new strategy?
-Mm. I just might.
-[gasps]
Attack it with your Dice Thrust.
That's the best chance we have.
If you miss this, it's over.
There's a one in six chance.
And the whole thing
comes down to your luck.
When the Embryo's eye is closed,
the fleshy armor covering it
has 88 Defense.
And when your Dice Thrust
landed crits
against the Golden Raana,
you pierced its 200 Defense.
So it proves you can deal
massive damage
through brute force.
There's no need
for the standard strategy.
We should be able to destroy
the Embryo without that.
But it's up so high!
How am I ever
supposed to get up there?
[gasps]
[panting]
[grunts]
Acrobatic Amble!
No. If you tried that,
you'd make yourself
the perfect target
for its Sylph Cutter.
Uh, then what are we gonna do?
I can close the gap between us.
Huh?
[ELYMAS]
Just be ready to follow up.
If it all goes as planned,
I can use Shield Bash
to send you flying
directly within striking range.
[gasps]
This carries a lot of risk,
though.
[gasps]
If we fall short,
neither of us
will walk out of here alive.
[whimpers]
[gasps]
[Embryo laughing]
Gotta roll a six on Dice Thrust.
All right.
If that's our only choice,
we ought to give it
our best try.
So then,
don't you worry.
I promise I'm rolling a six.
Well, good luck, Ruche.
I'm counting on you
more than ever this time.
[grunts]
Right!
[ELYMAS] Vital Slice!
Now, Ruche! Jump!
[Ruche grunts]
-[ELYMAS] Shield Bash!
-[Ruche grunts]
-[yells]
-[ELYMAS] So far, so good.
Now all we can do
is hope luck is in our favor.
While battling
the second Golden Raana,
Ruche tried seven times in a row
and still couldn't manage
to roll a six.
I know that streak
doesn't mean anything,
but...
probability converges.
Dice Thrust!
[ELYMAS]
We'll just get one chance.
[grunts]
[ELYMAS] Please!
[straining]
[grunts]
-[Ruche gasps]
-[AUTOMATED VOICE] Miss.
[gasps sharply]
[gasps]
[Embryo laughs]
[grunts tensely]
[Embryo laughing]
Dice Thrust!
[ELYMAS]
We'll just get one chance.
- [Ruche grunts]
-[ELYMAS] Please!
[straining]
[grunts]
-[Ruche gasps]
-[AUTOMATED VOICE] Miss.
[both gasp sharply]
[Embryo laughs]
[grunts tensely]
[Embryo laughing]
[ELYMAS] We failed.
Though this may
have been the only way,
it was reckless of us
to put it all on the line
and gamble with our own lives.
-What'll we do?
-[Embryo continues laughing]
[ELYMAS] How are we
supposed to survive?
[clinks]
[grunts]
I can't start giving up now.
I need to at least tank
the Tin Knights.
Then Ruche can land safely.
[grunts]
[Ruche grunts]
[gasps]
[RUCHE] Acrobatic Amble!
[grunting]
♪
[gasps]
[Ruche grunts] Here it comes!
[Embryo gasps]
It's time for my final...
Dice Thrust!
[Embryo screams]
[yelling]
[chuckles]
[Embryo groans]
[thuds]
[Ruche grunts]
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
2,117 EXP acquired.
Level 39 has been reached.
[ELYMAS]
Now I'm beginning to realize.
I made one big mistake.
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Level 41 has been reached.
[♪ gentle music playing]
[ELYMAS]
The only thing I could do
was hold out hope
and pray that luck
would be on Ruche's side.
But when things didn't go
as planned,
she managed to press on
and seize victory
regardless of the odds.
[gasps]
Did I really beat it myself?
[Elymas chuckles softly] Ruche.
[gasps]
I would be dead right now
if it weren't for you.
So I want to thank you.
[whimpering]
[chuckles softly]
[gasps]
Uh, you do? No problem!
After all the time we've spent
exploring this dungeon together,
I think it's really boosted
my confidence a lot.
People always said my class
was completely useless
and called us no good.
But you and I have still found
a bunch of items out here.
Even Dice Thrust helped.
-But more than that...
-[gasps]
Huh?
...thanks for being you.
[squeals]
♪
[laughs]
Cline really screwed up,
didn't he?
[Ruche giggles]
[ELYMAS]
I'd only been judging people
by their different classes
and levels as well.
In that regard,
I'm no different
from my father or Cline.
I was just applying
different standards
than they do.
[sighs]
When I was being stubborn,
Ruche risked her life
to come back and rescue me.
On top of that,
her quick thinking
turned a desperate situation
around.
And she single-handedly
defeated the Embryo.
Grateful and devoted,
she's able to perform
far beyond her limits
when it counts the most.
There's nobody who's more
dependable than you are.
Oh, come on now.
I'm not that great. [giggles]
You're so silly, Mr. Elymas.
[giggles]
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
"The Upsetter" title
has been acquired.
Defeat a Dreamlord with a party
of two members or less
at a level 70% or lower
than the recommended level.
Attack and Speed increase by 15%
when engaging in battle
against higher-level enemies.
♪
[ELYMAS] This title is acquired
by defeating Dreamlords
at low level.
Since it was essential
in Magic World,
I was also planning
to get it here eventually.
But I never imagined
I'd be receiving it so soon.
[RUCHE] Hey, look!
They dropped some items!
Yay, two Tin Swords!
-[cheering]
-[ELYMAS] What? Seriously?
[AUTOMATED VOICE]
Tin Sword. Level 35.
Attack, plus nine.
Market price, 2,400,000 gold.
A Tin Knight's sword.
[ELYMAS] Seems like she's always
making it rain valuable items.
The benefits of the Lady Luck
skill tree are absolutely huge.
But it takes a lot of courage
to walk around
with those equipped.
Hopefully, the Embryo
dropped something good as well.
-[Ruche cheering]
-Hey, Ruche.
Did you notice a bow
with a wind-type enchantment
skill over there?
Well, I, uh, I'm not sure.
It's one of the Embryo's drops.
Guess I can't expect things
to go that well.
-[magical whoosh]
-[Elymas gasps]
A skill book?!
[panting]
Those have a way lower drop rate
than weapons.
Unbelievable!
This is for the Intermediate
Wind Magic skill tree,
which should come in handy.
[gasps]
It's well known that Skill Books
are fairly expensive.
And thanks
to the nobles hoarding them,
their value
has shot up considerably.
This is incredibly valuable!
-What's going on, Mr. Elymas?
-[Elymas gasps]
Why are you keeping
that item hidden?
-[ELYMAS] Oh, sorry.
-Hmm?
But we found something crazy.
This'll really make us a target.
To avoid drawing attention,
we'll have to sell it
to that old woman.
-[rumbling]
-[Ruche gasps]
[exclaims]
[gasps]
[gasps] Mr. Elymas, what's this?
Don't worry.
The Dreamlord was defeated,
so the dungeon's
disappearing now.
We'll be back outside
before you know it.
[RUCHE] Are you serious?
That was pretty scary.
All of this
is still really new to me.
Oh, should probably wait
to say this, but...
What?
Since we've been here,
we've earned
over 60 million gold.
Huh?
[ELYMAS] Yeah. That's just
a rough estimate, though.
[gasps]
[whimpers]
Ruche, are you okay?
Hey, what's wrong?
You... You were right.
You really should've waited
to tell me that.
[gasps]
[chuckles]
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[ELYMAS] Thanks to Ruche,
we were able
to defeat the Embryo.
She's such an incredible ally.
And she's managed to bring me
even closer to acquiring
a Fang of Smoldering Insanity
Skill Book.
At this point, I just need
to get a few more items,
and I'll have 50 million gold.
But something tells me
that greedy old woman
isn't going to make it easy,
even when I finally
do have enough to buy it.
Next time, "Negotiation."
For now, it's time for us
to celebrate
beating the dungeon.